iese.edu 2013-05-19

# Privacy Policy: IESE Business School

Confidentiality, professional secrecy and security are core values of **IESE University of Navarra** , which commits to ensuring the privacy of the user or visitor at all times and in all interactions. IESE is also committed to not collecting unnecessary information about the User and handling personal information which the User may provide through our website with extreme care.

In accordance with **Law 15/1999 on Personal Data Protection** , and Royal Decree 1720/2007 implementation of the Personal Data Protection Act, we inform you that the use of certain services on our website requires that you provide certain personal data through registration forms or by sending email messages, and that these will be **processed and incorporated into files owned and controlled by IESE**. The voluntary submission of personal information constitutes **explicit consent** to the treatment of the same and its incorporation into our files, albeit revocable, without retroactive effect, and the **acceptance of the handling conditions** expressed below.

We also inform you that all our files are legally registered in the Personal Data General Registry of the Spanish Data Protection Agency.

The data we request are appropriate, relevant and strictly necessary for the purposes for which they are collected, and **under no circumstances are you forced to provide them**. All **information** requested in our forms **must be provided** to comply with the purpose of the request, except for forms **marking required fields with an asterisk (*)**. You also certify that all information you provide is true, accurate and relevant to the purpose for which it is being requested.

Our website requests and receives personal data via various forms and through e-mail with the **following purposes** and destined for the following files:

a. Students (Education File):

  * Managing requests for access to academic programs.
  * Formalization, registration, administration, implementation, and development of academic programs and teaching activity at IESE.
  * Delivering services to students (insurance policies, program financing, etc.).
  * Vocational Guidance Services (Job Bank).
  * Segmentation and implementation of profiles, statistical studies of services and content used, tastes and preferences, surveys or forms.
  * Image and/or sound recordings in the IESE classrooms and facilities for purposes of teaching and publication of IESE activities and to be part of its historical photographic archive.
  * Mailing of related information as well as events and activities of the entity.
  * Mailing of publications, invitations, programs, newsletters and the like.
  * Historical archive of relationships with students.

b. Alumni (Alumni File):

  * Maintaining alumni relations.
  * Organization of activities and events for alumni.
  * Mailing of related information as well as events and activities of the entity.
  * Management of alumni portal.
  * Management of career opportunities and job bank.

c. Companies and Partners (Management File):

  * Management of our customers and partners.
  * Management of relationships between IESE clients, partners and students.
  * Maintaining relationships between the parties and delivery of IESE-related information.

d. Information and relationships with IESE (Contacts File):

  * Ensuring the continuity of relationships with people who have or have had dealings with the school.
  * Mailing of related information as well as events and activities of the entity.
  * Advertising and market research.
  * Mailing of publications, invitations, programs, newsletters and the like.

e. E-mail:

We also provide several email addresses so you can request any information, clarification or explanation. If you include personal data in your email, or if your email address contains personal information, you authorize us to incorporate it into our corresponding IESE files if deemed appropriate, under the stipulations of this privacy policy.

Please note that the acceptance of our privacy policy, provided you do not tell us otherwise, implies your **consent to receiving all kinds of information** by any means including electronic media—and even once the course is finished—which IESE or related entities send to report on their activities/news, courses, programs and any offer of services and products related to IESE’s activities. If you have provided us personal information about a third party or provide it to us in the future you must have informed said party of the stipulations herein and received approval prior to providing the data.

IESE reserves the **right to decide whether or not to add** your personal data to its files.

If you **do not wish** to receive our information and **commercial mailings** , or wish to **withdraw your consent** to the authorizations granted, and to exercise your **rights of access, rectification, cancellation** and **opposition** , you may write to IESE -InfoDat-, Av. Pearson 21, 08034 Barcelona or email InfoDat@iese.edu, providing a copy of your National Identity Card (DNI) or passport.

We assume that **if you do not indicate otherwise within thirty (30) days** following the acceptance of this privacy policy, you authorize us to carry out the data communication specified as well as the use of your data for any of the purposes described unrelated to the main purpose of your relationship with IESE.

IESE informs you that your data is treated confidentially and used internally and for the purposes indicated. Therefore, **we do not give them or communicate them to third parties** , except as provided for by law, and to entities and organizations directly related to the services or products purchased, to academic program students and alumni, to businesses interested in our students’ services and IESE-related schools in order to receive information related to our business. Consequently, users who are added into our Education and Contacts files **expressly consent to the international transfer of their data** to IESE Business School-New York or other countries where IESE may have business schools or organize academic programs, with the aim of receiving information of the school’s activities, invitations to events and any other information we think may be of interest.

Some **registration processes** are done via **EMBARK, a US-based company** , which means that all data you provide during the registration process will be subject to EMBARK's privacy policies, and once reported to IESE, by this privacy policy.

All **student data which third parties are authorized to access** in the context of established relationships with IESE shall be confidential and may not be used for purposes other than those agreed. The assignees of the data are required to comply with the obligations under the Personal Data Protection Act and are solely responsible for violations of those rules.

If you have provided us **personal information about a third party** or provide it to us in the future you must have informed said party of the stipulations herein and received approval prior to providing the data.

Likewise, unless we are otherwise informed at InfoDat@iese.edu, you expressly consent to have **images** (photo and video) captured of you during the course of academic programs and events in IESE facilities to be made **public** and be partially or totally **used** for non-profit purposes solely for **IESE** informational and promotional material such as brochures, ads, school magazines and newspapers, websites, blogs and school videos, without any time limitation.

In order to keep your **personal information up-to-date** , you must inform us of any changes. Otherwise, we will not be liable for the accuracy of the data on record. We assume that unless you deliberately cancel your personal data from our files you are still interested in being in our records so we can provide our services, send commercial information and maintain an archive of relationships with students in the future. Your **data will be kept in our files** until the person concerned explicitly asks for the data to be removed, even after the cancellation deadlines established by law, until IESE deems it appropriate and as long as it is appropriate for the established purposes.

Browsing through our site is taken as users’ explicit consent for the **use of "cookies"** and IP tracking. However, if users wish to, they can disable and/or remove cookies by following their browser instructions. Cookies do not provide personal information about users at any time. Cookies enhance the website navigation experience and allow us to gather data for statistical purposes such as: preferences, date of first visit, number of times you have visited, date of last visit, origin URL and domain name, browser used and screen resolution.

In response to the trust placed in us and taking into account the importance of protection and confidentiality your personal data requires, IESE informs you that it **has taken all necessary technical and organizational measures** to safeguard the security of the same in compliance with the requirements of **Royal Decree 1720/2007**. Nevertheless, the user should be aware that Internet security measures are not infallible or foolproof, which is why IESE shall not be held liable for such situations and their consequences.

IESE may modify this privacy policy to adhere to changes in personal data legislation or case law, so it requires users to read the policy every time data is provided to us over the Web.

IESE assumes no liability for the processing of your personal data in the web pages which can be accessed through various links on our website, or the security measures adopted by any other webpage that links to ours.
